{
  "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
  "name": "Hazardous Materials and Fire Protection",
  "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Who is responsible for providing workers with WHMIS training?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "the supplier of controlled products.",
        "a training institute or provider.",
        "The employee must obtain their own training.",
        "The employer must provide the training."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The employer must provide the training."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Employers are responsible to:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "provide a MSDS for each controlled product used in the workplace.",
        "inform all workers about chemical hazards at the work site.",
        "train workers about labels, MSDS and other identifiers.",
        "all of the above."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["all of the above."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Suppliers of controlled products are responsible to:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "train employees to safely dispose of hazardous products.",
        "provide SDS for controlled product they sell or import.",
        "provide extra labels for employees to use when transferring controlled products from the original container.",
        "visit work sites to ensure controlled products are labelled properly."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["provide SDS for controlled product they sell or import."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Employees are responsible to:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "classify controlled products.",
        "train other employees about WHMIS.",
        "apply workplace labels where and when required.",
        "ensure SDS are readily available."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["apply workplace labels where and when required."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "The key elements of WHMIS are:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "employee education, SDS and product labelling.",
        "Hazard Products Act, OHS and SDS.",
        "employee labelling, SDS and employer training.",
        "product labeling, OHS and Controlled Products Regulations."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["employee education, SDS and product labelling."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "The goal of WHMIS is to:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "ensure workers have containers for controlled products.",
        "ensure suppliers of controlled products provide training for all employees.",
        "protect the worker by providing information on hazardous materials.",
        "ensure that the requirements for information on hazardous materials are unique to the requirements of each province."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["protect the worker by providing information on hazardous materials."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "An SDS must be provided for each controlled product because they:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "provide only the essential information from the label and are easier to read in an emergency.",
        "contain the generic product names and are easier to locate and read than the labels on the containers.",
        "are only for the employerâ€™s use when an emergency arises, and they can be retrieved from a secure location.",
        "provide more detailed information than can be provided on a label."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["provide more detailed information than can be provided on a label."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "The supplier label is attached to the:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "container in which the product is shipped.",
        "container in which the product is stored.",
        "work site near where the product is used.",
        "invoice when the product is delivered."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["container in which the product is shipped."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "How do you identify a portable gasoline container that is approved for use? It:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "is approved under the Alberta Occupational Health and Safety Code.",
        "is approved by the Alberta Hazardous Materials Control Regulations.",
        "has a MSDS label affixed to the outside of the container.",
        "is approved by either one or both of the ULC or CSA."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["is approved by either one or both of the ULC or CSA."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Ventilation system requirements for the work site are found in the:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "provincial and national building codes.",
        "Alberta Occupational Health and Safety Code.",
        "WCB Worker Handbook.",
        "Alberta Construction Safety Association."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Alberta Occupational Health and Safety Code."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Before entering a confined workspace you should:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "assemble all necessary tools and equipment to ensure easy access while working in the confined space.",
        "contact your employer to obtain information on dangerous gases present in the confined workspace.",
        "discuss your work plan with other workers who may have worked in a similar confined space.",
        "use a gas detector to determine whether the area contains any dangerous fumes or gases."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["use a gas detector to determine whether the area contains any dangerous fumes or gases."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "What type of fire extinguisher is versatile in fighting different types of fires?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "regular dry chemical",
        "purple K dry chemical",
        "multi-purpose dry chemical",
        "dry powder"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["multi-purpose dry chemical"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "When should you not fight a fire for personal safety reasons? When:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "you are wearing fire retardant clothing (FRC).",
        "the fire could block your escape route.",
        "the fire extinguisher does not have an inspection certificate.",
        "you have not activated the fire alarm."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["the fire could block your escape route."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "What are the four steps of proper portable fire extinguisher use?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Pull the pin. Arm the extinguisher. Squeeze the handle. Touch the surface after the fire is out.",
        "Pull the pin. Aim the extinguisher. Sweep the extinguisher. Touch the surface after the fire is out.",
        "Pick up the extinguisher. Arm the extinguisher. Squeeze the handle. Sweep the extinguisher from side to side.",
        "Pull the pin. Aim the extinguisher. Squeeze the handle. Sweep the extinguisher from side to side."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Pull the pin. Aim the extinguisher. Squeeze the handle. Sweep the extinguisher from side to side."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "Which of the following portable fire extinguishers should be used to fight a small fire burning in a pile of discarded oily rags?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Class A only",
        "Classes A, B and C",
        "Class C only",
        "Class D and K"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Classes A, B and C"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "topicId": "e1e9e8a3-f82c-4656-9ed2-b56ef1c8b71a",
      "question": "A Class C fire involves:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "electrical equipment.",
        "combustible metals.",
        "flammable liquids.",
        "household combustibles."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["electrical equipment."],
      "explanation": ""
    }
  ]
}
